<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.01 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/html4/loose.dtd">
<!--
 ~ Copyright (c) 2005-2010, WSO2 Inc. (http://www.wso2.org) All Rights Reserved.
 ~
 ~ WSO2 Inc. licenses this file to you under the Apache License,
 ~ Version 2.0 (the "License"); you may not use this file except
 ~ in compliance with the License.
 ~ You may obtain a copy of the License at
 ~
 ~    http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0
 ~
 ~ Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing,
 ~ software distributed under the License is distributed on an
 ~ "AS IS" BASIS, WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY
 ~ KIND, either express or implied.  See the License for the
 ~ specific language governing permissions and limitations
 ~ under the License.
 -->
<html><head>
  <meta http-equiv="content-type" content="text/html; charset=iso-8859-1"></meta>
  
  <title>Global Modules - User Guide</title>
  <link href="../../admin/css/documentation.css" rel="stylesheet" type="text/css" media="all" />
  </head>

<body>

<h1>Global Module Configurations</h1>

<p>The WSO2 SOA platform has the capabilities of Axis2 to add modules to
extend its capabilities. The global modules will affect all the services
deployed within the server. If you want to globally engage a particular
module, click Manage > Modules > <strong>List. </strong>On the <strong>Deployed
Modules</strong> page, you can globally engage any listed module.</p>

<h2>Deploying Module Archives (.mar) </h2>

<p>A module is an archive file that bundles a set of classes, related
libraries and third party library dependencies. The WSO2 Carbon provides a user
friendly interface to engage, disengage and configure these modules. You can
learn more about Axis2 modules from the Axis2 manuals at: <a href="http://ws.apache.org/axis2/1_5_1/modules.html">http://ws.apache.org/axis2/1_5_1/modules.html</a>
</p>

<p>To upload your module archive, all the class files and the module.xml
descriptor file have to be available in the archive. </p>

<p>The folder structure of the module archive file will look as follows.</p>

<pre>
    Test.mar
        - META-INF
            - module.xml
    TestModule.class
    TestHandler.class
</pre>

<p><img alt="Adding modules" src="images/addmodule.png" height="209" width="1020"/></p>

<p style="font-style: italic;"><strong>Figure 1:</strong> Uploading module archive files. </p>

<ol>
  <li>In the navigator under Manage > Modules, click <strong>Add</strong>. The
    <strong>Add a Module</strong> page appears.</li>
  <li>Click <strong>Browse</strong> to select the module archive file (.mar)
    you want to upload. Multiple (.mar) archives can be uploaded by clicking on the "+" button.</li>
  <li>Click <strong>Upload</strong>. 
    If the file was uploaded successfully, a message will appear prompting
    you to restart the server to activate the module.</li><li>Click
    <strong>OK</strong>. 
  </li>
</ol>

<p>
Once the server has been restarted, the module will be active and displayed
on the <strong>Deployed Modules</strong> page. You can engage, disengage or
delete the module as required.</p>

<h2>Listing of Globally Engaged Modules</h2>

<p>The WSO2 Carbon management console provides you with an interface to engage,
disengage, configure or delete available modules. </p>

<p>The module list contains the following entries for each module. </p>
<ul>
  <li>Name </li>
  <li>Version </li>
  <li>Description </li>
  <li>Actions </li>
</ul>
<ol>
</ol>

<p>You can perform the following actions on engaged modules </p>
<ul>
  <li>Disengage: If the module is already engaged, you can disengage the
    module. </li>
  <li>Configure: Some modules can be configured. Use this option to access
    the configuration page of these modules. </li>
  <li>Engage: If the module is not already engaged, use this option to engage
    the module. </li>
  <li>Delete: Delete the module </li>
</ul>

<h3>Global Modules UI before engaging any module</h3>

<p><img alt="Global UI before engaging any thing" src="images/global-before.png" height="521" width="1020"/></p>

<p style="font-style: italic;"><strong>Figure 2:</strong> Available modules</p>

<p>All the available modules are shown above the currently engaged modules.
The WS-Addressing module is always globally engaged. This list will be
updated when you engage other available modules.</p>

<p>For example, the Throttle module is available to be configured globally.
Once you click the Configure icon, a new page appears with the configuring
options available for that module. </p>

<h3>Throttle Global Configuration UI</h3>

<p><img alt="Globally engaging throttling" src="images/global-throttling.png" height="348" width="1021"/></p>

<p style="font-style: italic;"><strong>Figure 3:</strong> Throttle Configuration</p>

<p>After you have engaged a module (for example, throttling), the
<strong>Global Configurations</strong> page will be updated.
(Figure: 4)</p>

<p>There are some modules (for example, savan), doesn't have a global configuration
page. But those can be globally engaged, just by clicking on the <strong>Engage</strong>
action and can be disengaged by clicking on the <strong>Disengage</strong> action.</p>

<h3>Global Configuration UI after engaging modules</h3>

<p><img alt="Global UI after engaging modules" src="images/global-after.png" height="573" width="1014"/></p>

<p style="font-style: italic;"><strong>Figure 4:</strong> After Engaging Modules</p>

</body></html>
