<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<!--
  ~  Copyright (c) 2009, WSO2 Inc. (http://www.wso2.org) All Rights Reserved.
  ~
  ~  WSO2 Inc. licenses this file to you under the Apache License,
  ~  Version 2.0 (the "License"); you may not use this file except
  ~  in compliance with the License.
  ~  You may obtain a copy of the License at
  ~
  ~    http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0
  ~
  ~  Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing,
  ~  software distributed under the License is distributed on an
  ~  "AS IS" BASIS, WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY
  ~  KIND, either express or implied.  See the License for the
  ~  specific language governing permissions and limitations
  ~  under the License.
  -->

<!DOCTYPE html
     PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD XHTML 1.0 Transitional//EN"
     "http://www.w3.org/TR/xhtml1/DTD/xhtml1-strict.dtd">
<html xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xml:lang="en" lang="en">
  <head>
    <meta http-equiv="content-type" content="text/html; charset=iso-8859-1"/>
    <title>
      WSO2 MB - Deployment Guide
    </title>
    <link href="css/mb-docs.css" rel="stylesheet"/>
    <link href="styles/dist-docs.css" rel="stylesheet" type="text/css" media="all"/>
  </head>
  <body xml:lang="en">
      [ <a href="docs_index.html"> Documentation Index </a> ]
    <h1>
      WSO2 Message Broker Server  (MB) Deployment Guide
    </h1>
    <p>Deploying the WSO2 MB correctly on your infrastructure is a vital task for the success
        of the usage of the MB. You should first analyze the requirement and then select the
        best matching deployment mode. There are different set of possible deployment modes with
        different configurations.
    </p>
    <h2>
      Available Deployment options
    </h2>
    <p>
      <a href="installation_guide.html">Standalone Deployment Guide</a> :
      Describes the default standalone installation and deployment of the MB
    </p>
    <p>
      <a>Clustered Deployment Guide</a> :
      Contains the information on deploying the Message Broker in a clustered environment, this particular guide
      explains the available options on a clustered deployment.
    </p>
      <h2>Clustered Deployment Guide </h2>
      <p> In clustered deployment of WSO2 message broker, there are several scenarios which can be implemented. Basically
      in WSO2 message broker, there are three components.
      </p>
      <ul>
                <li>Broker</li>
                <li>Cassandra Server</li>
                <li>Zoo Keeper Server</li>
      </ul>
      <p>By default, WSO2 mb is packed with all these three component. In a clustered setup, it is possible to have these
      three components separately and shared with each other.
      </p>
      <p>Here we are describing some of the possible deployment scenarios and it can be customized according to your
      requirement.</p>

      <h3> Deployment models</h3>
       <ul>
                <li><a href="cluster_scenario_01.html">Starting external cassandra server and zoo keeper server and point all broker nodes to them</a> </li>
                <li><a href="cluster_scenario_02.html">Starting external zoo keeper server and use the inbuilt cassandra server in ring model with broker nodes</a></li>
                <li><a href="cluster_scenario_03.html">Starting external cassandra server and use inbuilt zoo keeper server in ring model with broker nodes</a></li>
                <li><a href="cluster_scenario_04.html">Use inbuilt cassandra server and zoo keeper server for all the broker nodes</a></li>
                <li><a href="cluster_scenario_05.html">Use inbuilt cassandra server and zoo keeper server in a customized manner</a></li>
      </ul>

      <h2>

      Other Resources
    </h2>
    <p/>
    <p>
      <a href="http://wso2.org/library/mb">The WSO2 Oxygen Tank
      Library</a> : The Library contains articles, tutorials,
      presentations, and other knowledge base items published on The Oxygen
      Tank on different styles of deployments.
    </p>
  </body>
</html>
