<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.01 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/html4/loose.dtd">
<!--
 ~ Copyright (c) 2005-2010, WSO2 Inc. (http://www.wso2.org) All Rights Reserved.
 ~
 ~ WSO2 Inc. licenses this file to you under the Apache License,
 ~ Version 2.0 (the "License"); you may not use this file except
 ~ in compliance with the License.
 ~ You may obtain a copy of the License at
 ~
 ~    http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0
 ~
 ~ Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing,
 ~ software distributed under the License is distributed on an
 ~ "AS IS" BASIS, WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY
 ~ KIND, either express or implied.  See the License for the
 ~ specific language governing permissions and limitations
 ~ under the License.
 -->
<html>
	<head>
		<meta http-equiv="content-type" content="text/html; charset=iso-8859-1"></meta>
		<title> Cluster Management - User Guide</title>
        <link href="../../admin/css/documentation.css" rel="stylesheet" type="text/css" media="all"/>
	</head>
	<body style="font-family: Times New Roman,Times,serif; font-size: 12pt;">
    <h1>WSO2 Message Broker Cluster Management</h1>
    <p>When WSO2 Message Broker is running in clustered mode queues and topic subscriptions are distributed. Although
       This is transparent to the user, he may need to know what are the nodes in the cluster and how queue ownership
       has been dynamically decided. Cluster management feature is there to address that aspect of usability. </p>
    <p>Following capabilities are provided under Cluster Management:</p>

    <ul>
        <li>View Zookeeper coordination detail</li>
        <li>View Cassandra connection detail</li>
        <li>View how queue ownership has been decided</li>
        <li>View individual queue information node-wise</li>
    </ul>
    <h2>View Zookeeper coordination detail</h2>
        <p>WSO2 MB should be pointed to a running Apache Zookeeper server during cluster configuration. User can see
           that configuration here.</p>
        <p><img alt="" src="../images/zookeeper-connection.png"/></p>
        <p align="middle">Figure 1: Apache Zookeeper Connection</p>


    <h2>View Cassandra coordination detail</h2>
        <p>WSO2 MB uses Apache Cassandra as the Message Storage. Thus during cluster configuration MB instance should be
           pointed to a running Apache Cassandra server. That connection detail is shown here.</p>
        <p><img alt="" src="../images/cassandra-connection.png"/></p>
        <p align="middle">Figure 2: Apache Cassandra Connection</p>


    <h2>View how queue ownership has been decided</h2>
        <p>When clustered, each queue has a owner (handling the actual processing of the queue), which is dynamically decided
           considering the load distributed among the cluster nodes. If the user is interested to know what nodes process
           which queues, that information is listed to a table as below.</p>
        <p><img alt="" src="../images/nodewiseQueueWorkers.png"/></p>
        <p align="middle">Figure 3: Nodes and Queue Ownership</p>
        <p>This table lists all the nodes that is visible to the server accessed by the management console. After setting up
           the cluster, using this table users can verify that each server can see one another in the cluster. </p>
        <p>After each node, it shows how many queues are owned by that server node. This is analogous to the workload owned by each
           node in the cluster for queues defined. When the number is clicked user, is navigated for individual queue information. </p>


    <h2>View individual queue information node-wise</h2>
        <p>This shows the names of the queues owned by the node clicked above. Also number of messages yet to be delivered
           is also shown.</p>
        <p><img alt="" src="../images/nodeQueues.png"/></p>
        <p align="middle">Figure 4: Nodes Specific Queues</p>

    <h2>What is node ID?</h2>
        <p>Node ID is assigned to each node joined in the cluster, giving a unique way to identify each node. This is useful for
           troubleshooting. Each node is considered as a peer, and there's no master-slave concept in WSO2 Message Broker. In
           following window it shows the node id been assigned to the node plus whether node is configured to be clustered
           or running in standalone mode. </p>
        <p><img alt="" src="../images/nodeIDBox.png"/></p>
        <p align="middle">Figure 5: Node ID and Running Mode</p>






























	</body>
</html>
